import module1Level1 from "../models/module1Level1";

export const level1Data = new module1Level1(
    {
        passage:
          'Every April, alongside various bird species, the swallow embarks on its migration to spend the summer months in northern Europe, Russia, Iran, and parts of Siberia, where it will breed and nurture its offspring. The swallow is widely recognized across its habitat for a multitude of reasons. Firstly, its distinctive features, including a forked tail and acrobatic flight patterns, set it apart. Secondly, it is a common sight, often cohabiting with human settlements, especially in rural areas, similar to its close relative, the house martin. However, encounters with swallows in urban environments are infrequent. Throughout history, people have observed swallows, noting their arrival and feeding behaviors. In various countries, these observations have become embedded in proverbs or sayings. In England, for instance, the saying "one swallow does not a summer make" is used to comment on unpredictable late spring weather. Similarly, the belief that "swallows are flying low" is thought to predict rainy or stormy weather. While there may be some truth to these observations, it is the insects swallows feed on that seem more responsive to the barometric pressure changes heralding a storm. In such conditions, insects and the swallows hunting them tend to stay closer to the ground. As the summer season concludes, swallows often gather in large numbers on elevated perches like roof ridges and telegraph wires, signaling the arrival of autumn when people remark that "the swallows are gathering." Around mid-September, swallows embark on their departure, typically leaving on the same day. Thousands are present one day, and the next, none can be found until the following spring. For centuries, this migration has puzzled people. The naturalist Gilbert White, writing in the late eighteenth century, speculated that swallows dove into ponds and rivers in autumn, residing in the bottom mud throughout the winter, only to re-emerge in spring. While this theory may seem extraordinary to us, White\'s lack of means to determine the truth led him to make a speculative guess. While it is now established that swallows undergo migration, there remain lingering queries. The reasons behind their extensive journeys, venturing far beyond the shores of the Mediterranean, prompt curiosity. Why do they not opt to linger in more temperate regions? The majority of swallows continue their migration to equatorial Africa, with some venturing even further south. Additionally, intriguing patterns emerge as populations of swallows bred in distinct countries exhibit diverse wintering destinations. For instance, those from France, Germany, and a considerable portion of Western Europe predominantly migrate to East Africa, finding refuge in places like Kenya or Tanzania. One of the most puzzling aspects revolves around the navigation capabilities of these birds, each weighing approximately twenty grams. How do they navigate across formidable obstacles such as mountain ranges, vast oceans, and arid deserts to reach their wintering grounds in the southern hemisphere? Equally baffling is their ability to return the following year to the precise location of their birth and, in some instances, to the very same nest. The intricacies of these migratory journeys raise profound questions about the innate navigational skills and mechanisms that enable such precision in these seemingly delicate creatures. Birds employ various navigation methods, utilizing the sun and detecting the Earth\'s magnetic field. Nocturnal migratory species also rely on the stars for navigation during their journeys covering vast distances. The precise return to familiar locations, such as fields or nests, seems to be linked to the imprinting of local landmarks on the memories of young birds as they traverse the area in the weeks before departure. Despite their remarkable navigational abilities, the migration journey poses significant risks. Birds often avoid long sea crossings, where food and water resources are limited. In Western Europe, for instance, most swallows opt for the Straits of Gibraltar or traverse the length of Italy before embarking on the comparatively shorter crossing to Tunisia in North Africa. However, unforeseen storms can blow them off course, leading to exhausted swallows seeking refuge on ships in the vast Atlantic Ocean. Additionally, they must navigate challenging terrain, including mountain ranges with unpredictable weather and scarce food. The coastal regions of North Africa present their own perils, as many young swallows fall prey to Eleonora\'s falcons, which strategically time their breeding to coincide with the southward migration of these fledglings. However, the most perilous segment of the journey is the Sahara Desert crossing. In this harsh environment, with minimal food and water, sandstorms further impede the already weakened birds, resulting in a substantial mortality rate. Estimates suggest that around 50 percent of adult birds and up to 80 percent of young birds may succumb to the challenges. Despite these harsh conditions, enough birds survive to ensure the continuity of the species.',
      },
      {
        questions: [
          {
            id: 0,
            question: "",
            options: [],
            correctAnswer: "",
          },
          {
            id: 1,
            question:
              "The swallow stands as the sole bird species that migrates to northern Europe for the summer.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "True" },
              { key: "B", value: "False" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "B",
          },
          {
            id: 2,
            question:
              "Its tail and distinctive flight pattern make the swallow easily identifiable.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "True" },
              { key: "B", value: "False" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "A",
          },
          {
            id: 3,
            question: "Urban areas often witness frequent sightings of swallows.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "True" },
              { key: "B", value: "False" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "B",
          },
          {
            id: 4,
            question:
              "Stormy weather seems to be predicted by the presence of insects rather than the swallows themselves.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "True" },
              { key: "B", value: "False" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "A",
          },
          {
            id: 5,
            question: "White's theory appears peculiar to contemporary observers.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "True" },
              { key: "B", value: "False" },
              { key: "C", value: "Not Given" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "A",
          },
          {
            id: 6,
            question:
              "Previously, the autumnal whereabouts of swallows remained_________.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "unknown" },
              { key: "B", value: "uncertain" },
              { key: "C", value: "unexplored" },
              { key: "D", value: "unchanged" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "B",
          },
          {
            id: 7,
            question:
              "Unable to confirm the fate of the swallows, White formulated a hypothesis________.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "about their migration patterns." },
              { key: "B", value: "regarding their behavior during mating season." },
              {
                key: "C",
                value: "concerning their adaptation to urban environments.",
              },
              { key: "D", value: "about their diving into ponds and rivers." },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "D",
          },
          {
            id: 8,
            question:
              "Despite our awareness of swallow migration, lingering questions persist regarding______.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "their preferred habitats." },
              { key: "B", value: "their choice of food sources." },
              { key: "C", value: "the reasons behind their extensive journeys." },
              { key: "D", value: "their social interactions." },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "C",
          },
          {
            id: 9,
            question:
              "At times, swallows have been seen not only returning to the same area but also revisiting it______.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "for breeding purposes" },
              { key: "B", value: "to explore new territories" },
              { key: "C", value: "to migrate further" },
              { key: "D", value: "to reclaim the very same nest." },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "D",
          },
          {
            id: 10,
            question: "Nocturnal avian travelers rely on the guidance of_____.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "the moon" },
              { key: "B", value: "landmarks" },
              { key: "C", value: "the sun" },
              { key: "D", value: "the stars" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "D",
          },
          {
            id: 11,
            question:
              "The navigation abilities of birds seem linked to their memory of_______.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "seasonal changes" },
              { key: "B", value: "their previous flights" },
              { key: "C", value: "local landmarks" },
              { key: "D", value: "magnetic fields" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "C",
          },
          {
            id: 12,
            question:
              "Choose TWO letters, A-F. Which pair of hazards confronted swallows during migration is referenced in the text?",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "The arid expanse known as the Sahara Desert" },
              { key: "B", value: "Extended journeys over the open sea" },
              { key: "C", value: "Insufficient nesting sites" },
              { key: "D", value: "Sailors experiencing hunger" },
              { key: "E", value: "Falcons belonging to the Eleanora's species" },
              { key: "F", value: "The voyage to Tunisia" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: ["A", "B"],
          },
          {
            id: 13,
            question: "Technology has had a profound ________on our lives.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "effect" },
              { key: "B", value: "impact" },
              { key: "C", value: "influence" },
              { key: "D", value: "result" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "B",
          },
          {
            id: 14,
            question: "The area has _______significant changes in recent years.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "undergone" },
              { key: "B", value: "experienced" },
              { key: "C", value: "witnessed" },
              { key: "D", value: "encountered" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "B",
          },
          {
            id: 15,
            question:
              "Planting trees can have a ________effect on the economy of arid areas.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "cascading" },
              { key: "B", value: "rippling" },
              { key: "C", value: "positive" },
              { key: "D", value: "negative" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "A",
          },
          {
            id: 16,
            question:
              "Deforestation can have unexpected __________for the ecology of a region.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "repercussions" },
              { key: "B", value: "results" },
              { key: "C", value: "outcomes" },
              { key: "D", value: "consequences" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "D",
          },
          {
            id: 17,
            question:
              "It is sometimes challenging to _______the exact nature of a problem.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "determine" },
              { key: "B", value: "figure out" },
              { key: "C", value: "pinpoint" },
              { key: "D", value: "identify" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "C",
          },
          {
            id: 18,
            question:
              "To attain optimal results, it is crucial to _______change at a local level.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "instigate" },
              { key: "B", value: "ignite" },
              { key: "C", value: "trigger" },
              { key: "D", value: "spark" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "A",
          },
          {
            id: 19,
            question:
              "The primary factor _______to success in any organization is a content and satisfied workforce.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "contributes" },
              { key: "B", value: "leads" },
              { key: "C", value: "attributes" },
              { key: "D", value: "relates" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "A",
          },
          {
            id: 20,
            question:
              "The climate has played a _______role in shaping this region's economic history.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "dominant" },
              { key: "B", value: "key" },
              { key: "C", value: "central" },
              { key: "D", value: "pivotal" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "D",
          },
          {
            id: 21,
            question:
              "Government intervention has had a ________ for regional growth.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "positive outcome" },
              { key: "B", value: "catalytic effect" },
              { key: "C", value: "stimulating effect" },
              { key: "D", value: "favorable result" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "B",
          },
          {
            id: 22,
            question:
              "__________can bring about a transformation in people's behavior.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "Shock tactics" },
              { key: "B", value: "Radical methods" },
              { key: "C", value: "Extreme measures" },
              { key: "D", value: "Unconventional strategies" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "A",
          },
          {
            id: 23,
            question: "__________is much more acceptable than rapid change.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "Gradual progress" },
              { key: "B", value: "Slow advancement" },
              { key: "C", value: "Steady development" },
              { key: "D", value: "Incremental improvement" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "A",
          },
          {
            id: 24,
            question:
              "The introduction of new farming practices has had a _________on people's lives.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "profound influence" },
              { key: "B", value: "profound impact" },
              { key: "C", value: "significant impact" },
              { key: "D", value: "remarkable change" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "B",
          },
          {
            id: 25,
            question:
              "To achieve the most_________, the countries involved need to engage in negotiations.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "favorable outcome" },
              { key: "B", value: "desirable outcome" },
              { key: "C", value: "beneficial deal" },
              { key: "D", value: "successful resolution" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "A",
          },
          {
            id: 26,
            question:
              "The solution in this particular case is elusive and_________.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "hard to find" },
              { key: "B", value: "not easy to find" },
              { key: "C", value: "challenging to comprehend" },
              { key: "D", value: "tough to attain" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "B",
          },
          {
            id: 27,
            question:
              "The substantial amounts of money invested had only a ________on the neighborhood.",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "negligible effect" },
              { key: "B", value: "minimal impact" },
              { key: "C", value: "insignificant influence" },
              { key: "D", value: "small consequence" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "B",
          },
          {
            id: 28,
            question:
              "The wasteland was totally metamorphosed. (completely)_________",
            options: [
              { key: "A", value: "Identical Meaning" },
              { key: "B", value: "Equivalent Meaning" },
              { key: "C", value: "Same Meaning" },
              { key: "D", value: "Synonymous Meaning" },
            ],
            correctAnswer: "C",
          },
        ],
      }
);
